[Music]
[音乐]
okay good afternoon
好的，下午好
so we decided to stay till the end you
所以我们决定待到最后
must be tired after such a long day of
这么漫长的一天之后，一定要累
really nice talks and I really glad that
非常好的谈话，我真的很高兴
you actually actually came here because
你实际上是来这里的，因为
it is almost one of the one of the last
它几乎是最后一个之一
talks during this day and yeah let's go
在这一天的谈话，是的，我们走吧
did you know that Business Process
你知道业务流程吗
Management market is currently worth
目前管理市场值得
around 8 billion dollars and I can tell
大约80亿美元，我可以说
you even more by 2025 it will be worth
到2025年，您将更加值得
around 18 and a half billion dollars
大约18亿美元
why would companies invest such
公司为什么要投资这样
incredibly huge amount of money into
巨额资金流入
BPMS and the answer is pretty simple
BPMS，答案非常简单
actually because business processes I
其实是因为我的业务流程
would define how our companies make
将定义我们公司的生产方式
money how they are competitive or simply
金钱如何竞争或简单
how they live in the complex world of
他们如何生活在复杂的世界中
legal regulations and wherever we come
法律法规，无论我们走到哪里
from our companies are pretty much the
来自我们公司的
same they want to earn money and reduce
他们想赚钱并减少
their costs that's why they try to
他们的成本，这就是为什么他们试图
optimize and automate their business
优化和自动化他们的业务
processes and they often do it just by
流程，而他们通常只是通过
buying and off-the-shelf solution
购买和现成的解决方案
already product and there's completely
已经产品，并且完全
nothing wrong about this at the same
同时没有错
time though we developers are often used
时间虽然我们开发人员经常使用
to follow agile software development
跟随敏捷软件开发
principles we know how to utilize the
我们知道如何利用
main driven design micro services to
主要驱动设计微服务
actually deliver products of higher
实际交付更高的产品
quality and delivered them much quicker
质量并更快地交付它们
the question now is how can we reconcile
现在的问题是我们如何调和
business process management systems with
业务流程管理系统
the idea of micro services and agile
微服务和敏捷的想法
software development during this
在此期间进行软件开发
presentation
介绍
we will together try to find the answer
我们将一起努力寻找答案
to this question we will also see how
对于这个问题，我们还将看到
tools from spring ecosystem will help us
春季生态系统的工具将帮助我们
achieving this goal this talk will be a
实现这个目标，这次演讲将是
bit different
有点不同
probably from all the others that you
可能来自其他所有的人
that you've been during this conference
您在这次会议期间去过的地方
because I would like to keep this on a
因为我想保持这个
high level of abstraction not digging
高层次的抽象而不是挖掘
too deep into the technical details of
太深的技术细节
each tool I want you to get the general
我想让您掌握的每种工具
idea and understand the approach that we
想法并了解我们的方法
can take in order to find the answer and
可以采取以找到答案和
my name is Bert Thomas wada I come from
我叫伯特·托马斯·瓦达
Warsaw Poland and I also come here to
华沙波兰和我也来这里
you as a person that spent around four
您作为一个花费了大约四倍的人
years
年份
automating business processes both for
自动化业务流程
custom solutions and of the shelf ones
定制解决方案和货架解决方案
as well and I've been there I went
我也去过那里
through the good and through the bad
通过好与坏
sides of this kind of systems and today
这种系统的两面以及今天
I am a consultant of batagor IT mines
我是batagor IT矿山的顾问
which is a Polish company and with the
这是一家波兰公司，
consent of our clients I can actually
得到我们客户的同意
share these some details about what I'm
分享有关我的一些细节
doing professionally today and I
我今天在做专业
carefully work for a bottom file which
仔细工作的底层文件
is Swedish power company whose mission
是瑞典电力公司，其使命
is fossil-free in one generation and
一代都不含化石，
vattenfall is also in mobility services
vattenfall也在移动服务中
and infrastructure including charging
和基础设施，包括收费
stations for Tesla or other electric
特斯拉或其他电力站
vehicles and of course web services for
车辆，当然还有网络服务
the users and within the last few years
用户以及最近几年
the cooperation between but a great
之间的合作却很棒
minds and Vattenfall IT services in
思维和Vattenfall IT服务
Katowice bond resulted in a 5-time
卡托维兹债券导致5次
increase the number of available
增加可用数量
charging stations and today we are in
充电站，今天我们在
the progress of migrating the mobility
迁移的进度
platform into new micro service
平台进入新的微服务
environment running on kubernetes
在kubernetes上运行的环境
clusters in Microsoft Azure cloud and
Microsoft Azure云中的群集和
tools that we are using on daily basis
我们每天使用的工具
include Java 11 spring with Apache Kafka
在Apache Kafka中包含Java 11 spring
and this is another reason why I'm
这是我之所以的另一个原因
standing here in front of you talking
站在你面前说话
about micro services it's been over
关于微服务已经结束了
three years already since I started
自从我开始三年
working with micro services
使用微服务
professionally and before we get into
专业并且在我们进入之前
main topic let's meet Bruce Bruce is a
让我们认识布鲁斯是布鲁斯的主要话题
software engineer
软件工程师
he has like seven years of experience
他有七年的经验
he's been working on automating business
他一直在致力于业务自动化
processes for quite some time already
已经处理了一段时间
and it's very passionate about micro
而且对微电子充满热情
services he goes to conferences just as
他参加会议的服务就像
we do here it's books he's very fond of
我们在这里做他非常喜欢的书
the main driven design and you know what
主要驱动的设计，你知道什么
he struggles a lot in his project people
他在项目中挣扎很多
are quitting the company are very
正在辞职的公司非常
frustrated it's very hard to produce a
沮丧的是很难产生一个
single change in the system it's even
系统中的单一变化，甚至
hard to find the line code that should
很难找到应该的行代码
be modified in order to provide this
进行修改以提供此功能
change they cannot find the common the
改变他们找不到共同点
common ground with business people but
与商界人士有共同点，但
Bruce is not like all his colleagues he
布鲁斯并不像他的所有同事一样
wants to stay in the company and he
想留在公司，他
feels that micro services can actually
认为微服务实际上可以
help him and his company to save the
帮助他和他的公司挽救
project but he has no idea how to apply
项目，但他不知道如何申请
the idea of micro services into BPMS we
将微服务引入BPMS的想法
will try to help Bruce out with his
会尽力帮助布鲁斯
problem and before we do so we know what
问题，在我们这样做之前，我们知道了什么
micro services are all about and one
微服务是关于一个的
bpms are all about
BPM都是关于
you won't hear from me any vendor
您不会收到我的任何供应商的消息
related stuff will just do micro
相关的东西只会做微
services alright if you ask Bruce what
服务好，如果你问布鲁斯
micro services mean to him he would tell
微服务对他来说意味着他会告诉
you something that I told him like
你跟我说过的话
hundreds of times micro services are all
数百倍的微服务
about the autonomy what is the autonomy
关于自治是什么自治
autonomy is multi dimensional vector
自治是多维向量
consisting of six dimensions the most
最多由六个维度组成
important one is scalability we scale
重要的是我们扩展的可扩展性
our services for numerous reasons for
我们提供服务的原因有很多
example we may need to deal with a
例如我们可能需要处理
bigger load the traffic is getting
流量越来越大
higher so we may scale our services
更高，因此我们可以扩展我们的服务
vertically by adding new resources like
通过添加新资源（例如
CPU or memory or we may scale our
CPU或内存，否则我们可能会扩展规模
services horizontally back new instances
服务水平支持新实例
of our service another reason for
我们服务的另一个原因
scaling is that we want to be resilient
扩展是我们想要保持弹性
in case of failure and then vertical
如果失败，然后垂直
scalability won't give us much we
可扩展性不会给我们太多
usually just add new instances but what
通常只是添加新实例，但是
I really want to tell you is that
我真的想告诉你的是
scalability is not only about technical
可扩展性不仅与技术有关
stuff application in his lifetime might
他一生中的东西应用程序可能
get to the moment where the size the
到大小的那一刻
complexity the technical depth may reach
技术深度可能达到的复杂性
such a high level that the the system
如此高的水平，以至于系统
won't be scalable from organizational or
无法从组织机构扩展或
cost perspective and this is such
成本角度，就是这样
example is very well described by Uncle
叔叔很好地描述了这个例子
Bob in his book entitled clean
鲍勃在他的书《干净》中
architecture when he actually
当他真正的建筑
the real company and tell us about some
真正的公司，并告诉我们一些
some measures some indicators about how
一些措施有关如何
things change release by release and
事情因发布而改变
what you can see here on the first
您可以在这里首先看到的是
figure is that the number of Engineers
数字是工程师人数
that are required to develop and
发展所需要的
maintain the product is drastically
彻底维护产品
rising release by release at the same
在同一发布中不断发布
time the number of lines of code
时间代码行数
business line of lines of code that are
业务线的代码行是
being written in every iteration is
在每次迭代中被编写为
decreasing which means that the unit
减少意味着单位
cost of a single business line of code
单个业务代码行的成本
is getting higher and higher the more
越来越高
people we have the least code we write
我们编写的代码最少的人
the lower the productivity is and what
生产率越低，什么
our CEO sees now is that our IT
我们的首席执行官现在看到的是我们的IT
department no longer costs like 1
部门的成本不再像1
million dollars it cost like 20 million
一百万美元，它花了大约两千万
dollars so you can see how crucial it is
美元，所以您可以看到它有多重要
to take care of organizational
照顾组织
scalability as well and regarding the
以及可扩展性
autonomy each part of our system each
自治我们系统的每个部分
component should be scalable
组件应该是可扩展的
independently just as our organization
就像我们的组织一样独立
does
确实
so here's Bruce you're struggling a lot
所以这是布鲁斯，你在挣扎很多
in producing any single change there's a
在产生任何单一变化的过程中
frustration there's productivity is very
无奈那里的生产力非常
low so we need to help us out in this
低，所以我们需要在这方面帮助我们
area as well another dimension of the
面积以及
autonomy vector is deployment the way
自主向量是部署的方式
each micro service is being deployed
每个微服务都在部署
including
包含
deployment frequency should be an
部署频率应为
individual decision of a team that
团队的个人决定
actually it's managing is responsible
实际上它的管理是负责任的
for this particular service of course we
对于这种特殊的服务，我们当然
usually we usually aim for having like a
通常我们通常的目标是像
consistent deployment schema throughout
贯穿始终的一致部署架构
the company throughout all our teams but
整个团队中的公司
there are big components like ACLs for
像ACL这样的大型组件
example or companies that are working
例子或正在工作的公司
under strict legal regulations but need
根据严格的法律法规，但需要
to follow some other unique software
跟随其他一些独特的软件
development lifecycle but anyway how to
开发生命周期，但无论如何
provide deployment autonomy we need to
提供我们需要的部署自主权
make our services as independent as
使我们的服务与
possible how to provide this
可能如何提供这个
independence through high cohesion
高凝聚力的独立性
providing high cohesion
提供高凝聚力
and in a nutshell it means that the
概括地说，这意味着
logic microservices contained must be
包含的逻辑微服务必须是
concentrated on concrete business
专注于具体业务
functionalities and not leaked to other
功能，不泄漏给其他人
services micro services are not only
服务微服务不仅
about the code these are databases as
关于这些代码是数据库
well and each micro service should
好，每个微服务都应该
manage data itself you should manage the
管理数据本身，您应该管理
data it is responsible for itself
数据对自己负责
securing the access database and not
保护访问数据库而不是
allowing any out of service you actually
允许您实际上停止服务
access the schema or modify data and
访问架构或修改数据，以及
dividing our business into parts lets us
将我们的业务分为几部分
choose technologies that are appropriate
选择合适的技术
for the complexity of the problem that
对于问题的复杂性
we are currently solving we may as
我们目前正在解决，我们可能会
different set of technologies for
不同的技术
complex business logic we may use
我们可能使用的复杂业务逻辑
different set of technologies direct for
直接针对不同的技术
example spring data rest for cloud
云的春季数据样本示例
applications and at the same time we may
申请，同时我们可能
also experiment with new technologies
也尝试新技术
and some single services not impacting
和一些单一服务不影响
the whole system so that we can be more
整个系统，以便我们可以更多
competitive in the market um in the
在市场上具有竞争力
world of distributed systems failures
分布式系统故障世界
and in are inevitable they will happen
并且不可避免地会发生
so why would a counting module for
那么为什么要使用一个计数模块
example failure block the possibility of
示例故障阻止了
reading charging sessions of my Tesla
阅读我的特斯拉充电会议
right the autonomy is also the autonomy
对，自治也是自治
of failure each micro service that fails
失败的原因每个失败的微服务
should impact other services in the
应该会影响
smallest possible extent and finally
最小程度，最后
nothing would have happened if it hadn't
如果没有的话，什么也不会发生
been for people micro services can only
为人们服务的微服务只能
work in places where the organizational
在组织工作的地方工作
culture is ready to give teams the
文化已经准备好给团队
autonomy the possibility to take care of
自主照顾的可能性
the product end to end from the very
产品从头到尾
beginning from the first analysis
从第一个分析开始
throughout the whole lifecycle and they
在整个生命周期中，他们
need to let the leadership in each team
需要让每个团队的领导
to show up itself there is no place for
出现自己没有地方
command and control how many times were
命令和控制多少次
angry and how things work in your
生气以及你的事情如何运作
project how things are communicating
预测事物如何交流
between each other we are getting
彼此之间，我们越来越
frustrated very often right and it
经常感到沮丧，对吧
didn't happen just like that
不是那样发生的
according to Conway's law the man over
根据康威定律，
here
这里
every organization will eventually
每个组织最终都会
create a system that mirrors
创建一个镜像的系统
communication schemes from the company
公司的沟通计划
and we developers often tend to ignore
我们开发人员经常会忽略
business know how to write code we don't
业务知道如何编写我们不知道的代码
need to talk to them right and do you
需要正确地与他们交谈，你呢
know what happens with this ignorance it
知道这种无知会发生什么
is put it into the code committed and
被放入提交的代码中，
pushed to get what should we do instead
力求得到我们应该怎么做
instead we should talk with these people
相反，我们应该与这些人交谈
try to find the common ground try to
尝试找到共同点尝试
find out what are the real business
找出什么是真正的生意
processes where is the value where do we
价值在哪里
earn money where do we lose money etc
赚钱，我们在哪里赔钱等
and only when we are on the same page we
只有当我们在同一页面上时，
can really create real bounded context
可以真正创建真实的有界上下文
and thus provide truly cohesive
从而提供真正的凝聚力
microservices autonomous micro services
微服务自治微服务
and that's why we should advise Bruce to
这就是为什么我们应该建议布鲁斯
start with event storming events
从事件风暴事件开始
storming is a workshop based method for
风暴是一种基于车间的方法
exploring business domains business
探索业务领域业务
proceeds and it is incredibly engaging
继续前进，令人难以置信
effective easy and fun as well big
有效容易又有趣
picture event storming session which is
图片事件风暴会话是
one of the possible variations of this
可能的变化之一
workshop gathers people from different
研讨会聚集了来自不同地方的人们
areas stakeholders business people
地区利益相关者商界人士
analyst architects developers
分析架构师开发人员
whoever can have some insights into the
谁可以对
problem that we are currently working on
我们目前正在研究的问题
and leaving the room after such workshop
在这样的工作坊之后离开房间
every participant has the same level of
每个参与者的水平相同
knowledge during this workshop we all
我们在这次研讨会上的知识
can understand where is the real problem
可以了解真正的问题在哪里
how the business process looks like what
业务流程看起来如何
are the business rules that drives the
是驱动
process where we lose money where we
我们在哪里赔钱的过程
gain money where we gain reputation
在我们赢得声誉的地方赚钱
where we lose the reputation where the
我们失去声誉的地方
problems were priorities and it also
问题是重中之重
gives us the base for further work like
为我们提供了进一步的工作基础，例如
design level tactical sessions where we
设计级战术会议
can actually get the meet for us
可以真正满足我们
aggregates the entities the domain
聚合域中的实体
driven design building blogs etc why we
驱动设计，建筑博客等为什么我们
are talking about this in terms of
在谈论这个方面
business proceeds
商业收益
because in every company people tend to
因为在每个公司里，人们倾向于
do two things first do their job well
先做好两件事
which is naturally good and second
这自然是好的，第二
ignore what happens outside the team or
忽略团队之外发生的事情，或者
the department and this ignorant like we
该部门和像我们这样的无知
already mentioned it is very dangerous
已经提到这是非常危险的
as we may lose the big picture and don't
因为我们可能会失去大局，不要
know how things influence each other so
知道事物如何相互影响
this is how silos are born and business
这就是筒仓的诞生和经营方式
in every organization mine yours yours
在每个组织中，属于您的属于您
and yours in the back is the same and
和你在后面是一样的
it's never restricted to one type of
它永远不会局限于一种
operations in one silo only business
仅一家仓库的业务
always closed two silos always it means
总是关闭两个孤岛，总是意味着
that there is no single point of truth
没有单一的真理
in terms of understanding the business
在了解业务方面
process and it is also source of
过程，它也是
confusion because people from one
混乱，因为人们来自一个
department from one silo might use
一个筒仓的部门可能会使用
different definitions of the same term
同一术语的不同定义
that than all the others summing up a
比所有其他人总结一个
business problem is hard to solve hard
业务问题很难解决
to discuss and hard to visualize in this
在此进行讨论和难以想象
event storming that enables us to
事件风暴，使我们能够
overcome all these obstacles and work
克服所有这些障碍和工作
out the common vision with of the
与
business process that won't be based on
不会基于的业务流程
some UML or BPMN diagrams provided birth
一些UML或BPMN图提供了出生
by analysts it will be a living well a
通过分析师，这将是一个很好的生活
living source of knowledge and similarly
知识的活生生之源
the business process implementation
业务流程实施
might cross different teams they print
可能会跨越他们打印的不同团队
micro services they need to communicate
他们需要交流的微服务
somehow each other and Bruce really
莫名其妙地彼此和布鲁斯
needs to start in here to actually
需要从这里开始
understand why does he have the mess in
了解他为什么会陷入困境
the code and what and understand what
代码和内容，了解什么
system is currently doing and what it is
系统当前正在做什么以及它在做什么
supposed to be doing and he knows where
应该在做，他知道在哪里
to start he knows what my services are
首先，他知道我的服务是什么
all about but he still has no idea about
关于一切，但他仍然不知道
how to apply micro services to BPMS so
如何将微服务应用于BPMS
let's ask Bruce what bpms is all about
让我们问一下布鲁斯，什么是bpm
and at the very high level most BPMS
在最高级别上，大多数BPMS
systems consist of following parts of
系统由以下部分组成
course this is just a general high-level
当然这只是一般的高级
overview
概观
they might be some other components as
他们可能是其他一些组件
well but let's keep it simple in the
好吧，但让我们保持简单
heart of HP PMS there's a thing called
HP PMS的心脏有一个叫做
workflow and
工作流程和
you can treat it as a black box that is
您可以将其视为黑匣子
just responsible for first execution
只负责第一次执行
including human tasks to service task
包括人工任务到服务任务
execution access control managing
执行访问控制管理
process metadata etc but the part the
处理元数据等，但部分
business is really looking for are those
企业真的在寻找那些
fancy why's they bite with their eyes
看中他们为什么咬他们的眼睛
they need to have a common view that
他们需要有一个共同的观点
actually eases their work will help them
真正减轻他们的工作压力将对他们有帮助
in the day everyday life and next
在日常生活中以及未来
valuable thing our reports business
我们的报告业务有价值的东西
needs to know how the processes are
需要知道流程如何
performing if they're earning money or
如果他们赚钱或
if they're losing money
如果他们赔钱
there are also process molars there
那里也有磨牙
where we can actually mold the process
在这里我们可以实际塑造过程
with some standard notations like BPM
带有一些标准符号，例如BPM
annotation and also some system
注释以及一些系统
integrations connectors that actually
实际上是集成连接器
enables us to integrate the bpms with
使我们能够将bpms与
all the other parts in the inner system
内部系统的所有其他部分
this is kind of a high-level overview
这是一个高级概述
let's take a look at the architecture
让我们来看看架构
now don't worry I will zoom it in these
现在不用担心，我会放大这些
are of course again this is a very
当然又是一个非常
simplified view there might be much more
简化的视图可能还有更多
blocks but let's keep it simple the user
块，但让用户保持简单
interacts with the system through some
通过一些与系统交互
fancy you eyes and let's say that it
看中你的眼睛，让我们说
eventually ends up in some can't you a
最终以一些你不能
controller with you a controller does is
控制器与您一起做的是
that it forwards requests to modules who
它将请求转发给谁
then usually within a model it like
然后通常在模型中
history and all the reporting user and
历史记录以及所有报告用户和
access management human tasks company
访问管理人员任务公司
task list and all tasks related stuff
任务列表和所有与任务相关的东西
ends up in workflow engine and all these
最终进入工作流引擎，所有这些
components actually use common usually
实际上通常使用的组件
relational database to persist the state
关系数据库保持状态
process the data the question now is
处理数据，现在的问题是
does this architecture aligned with the
该架构是否与
autonomy we've been talking about let's
我们一直在谈论的自主权
try to find out do we have scalability
尝试找出我们是否具有可扩展性
of time we don't we their scale the
时间的流逝，我们没有他们的规模
whole system or we don't scale at all do
整个系统，或者我们根本不扩展
we have technology autonomy we don't
我们拥有技术自主权
because we are constrained to use the
因为我们被限制使用
same set of technologies within all
所有领域内的同一套技术
business processes do we have deployment
我们有业务流程部署吗
autonomy we don't we either deploy the
自治我们不部署
whole system or we deploy nothing I know
整个系统，或者我们什么都不部署
one system actually that
一个系统实际上
allows us to deploy processes
允许我们部署流程
independently underneath there's still
独立地在下面
the same set of resources so if anything
相同的资源集，如果有的话
goes wrong we either get we either get
出了错我们要么得到要么要么得到
deployment autonomy or a zillion
部署自主权或不计其数
autonomy do we have data autonomy we
我们有数据自主权吗
don't every business process uses the
并非每个业务流程都使用
same generic database generic schema
相同的通用数据库通用架构
same tables and it's even very hard to
相同的桌子，甚至很难
extract the data related to one
提取与一个相关的数据
particular business process and in terms
特定业务流程和术语
of people tell me teams are usually
的人告诉我，团队通常
working on common code bases they need
在他们需要的通用代码库上工作
to schedule deployments constantly merge
安排部署不断合并
their changes resolve conflicts so these
他们的改变解决了冲突，所以这些
kinds of systems usually do not apply to
各种系统通常不适用于
the core idea of micro service or ton
微服务或吨的核心思想
and if you have any knowledge of any of
如果您对以下任何一项有所了解
the shelf solution that applies to this
适用于此的货架解决方案
just let me know how Bruce is developer
让我知道布鲁斯是如何发展的
might perceive it Bruce is very sad and
可能会觉得布鲁斯很伤心，
he said not only because this
他说不仅是因为
architecture from bpms does not apply to
bpms中的体系结构不适用于
the micro service autonomy he's also
他也是微服务的自主者
said because his work is very often
说，因为他的工作很频繁
manual in order to provide some change
手册以提供一些更改
he often needs to my only click through
他经常需要我唯一的点击
some UI management console to actually
一些UI管理控制台
create a view form or something he also
创建一个视图窗体或他还
needs to make some dirty hacks sometimes
有时需要做一些肮脏的骇客
to make things work and he cannot even
使事情起作用，他甚至不能
bump up the Java version from 7:00 to
将Java版本从7:00提升到
8:00 his technology plea constraint but
8:00他的技术请求受到限制，但
we as it as we advise Bruce here on a
我们照建议布鲁斯在这里
quick event storming session with his
与他的快速事件讨论会
colleagues for one of the process that
同事的过程之一
is actually present in in their company
实际上存在于他们的公司中
and the process is called address change
这个过程称为地址变更
let's have a look how it works
让我们看看它是如何工作的
whenever customer calls call center and
每当客户致电呼叫中心并
request the others change the call
请求其他人更改通话
center employee attempts the
中心员工尝试
authorization so the customer needs to
授权，因此客户需要
provide some customer password and if
提供一些客户密码，如果
it's correct the others change gets
是正确的，其他变化得到
authorized the others change is
授权其他人更改是
registered then the IML anti-money
然后注册IML反金钱
laundering process is getting started
洗钱程序正在开始
and based on the result whether the if
并根据结果是否
the I am I'll check it is positive then
我会检查它是否为阳性
we confirm the others change or if it's
我们确认其他更改，或者
not then we recall the others change and
然后我们不记得其他人在改变，
because Bruce is very fluent in BPM and
因为布鲁斯的BPM非常流利，
he's quickly sketched a diagram that
他很快画了一个图
corresponds to what we just modeled with
对应于我们刚刚建模的
sticky notes with the difference but
粘滞便笺，但有所不同
this diagram might not be readable for
该图可能不可读
everyone while sticky notes are readable
每个人都可以读取便签
for almost every person on earth these
对于地球上几乎每个人来说
are just sticky notes written by human
只是人类写的便签
with a pen Bruce made also enough
用钢笔布鲁斯也足够
analysis to assume that there will be
分析，假设会有
three micro-services authorizer that
三个微服务授权者
will be common for most business
对于大多数企业来说将是常见的
processes and will be responsible for
流程并将负责
authorizing customers that are calling
授权正在致电的客户
the call center customer contact
呼叫中心客户联系
responsible for managing customer
负责管理客户
contact information and email anti
联系信息和电子邮件反
monologic related processes these
这些与生物学相关的过程
services needs to communicate somehow
服务需要以某种方式进行沟通
and of course there are numerous
当然有很多
communication patterns that might even
甚至可能的沟通方式
be mixed within a company but we want to
在公司内部混在一起，但我们想
keep our services as autonomous as
保持我们的服务自治
possible and ask the couple as possible
尽可能问这对夫妻
so we'll just stick a synchronous
所以我们将保持同步
versions the synchronous options of
版本化的同步选项
communication what a synchronous options
通讯什么是同步选项
do we have them the first one is
我们有他们的第一个是
choreography how does it work well her
舞蹈编排她如何运作良好
ography assumes that there is no central
地理学假设没有中心
point in the system that would route
系统中要路由的点
messages among services and decide which
服务之间的消息并决定哪个
message should go where instead services
消息应该去哪里服务
emit event messages and don't care what
发出事件消息，不在乎
happens next on the other hand consumers
另一方面发生在消费者身上
read those messages and take for
阅读这些消息并接受
interactions and this pattern is called
相互作用，这种模式称为
event chain her ography in our case
事件链她在我们的情况下的摄影
would look like this client amazed the
看起来这个客户感到惊讶
others change requested event to the
其他人将请求的事件更改为
even boss authorizer who consumes it
甚至是消费它的老板授权人
will only analyze the the the successful
只会分析成功的
path okay the authorizer
授权者的路径还可以
sends back the other exchange authorized
退回授权的其他交易所
event this event is consumed by customer
事件此事件由客户使用
contact customer contact says that other
联系客户联系说其他
exchange was registered adverse change
交易所被注册不利变化
register is consumed by AM L AM L
寄存器由AM L使用AM L
returns the AM L check succeeded this is
成功返回AM L检查，这是
again consumed by a customer contact and
再次由客户联系人消耗，并且
address change confirmed gets back to
确认地址更改后返回
the client
客户端
in general hurrah graph is great way of
总的来说hurray图是
communication but in case of business
沟通，但有业务往来
processes we can identify some problems
我们可以发现一些问题的过程
what are they
这些是什么
authorization service listen to others
授权服务听别人
change request livin which is business
更改请求livin这是业务
process related event so anytime we want
处理相关事件，以便我们随时随地
to add a new business process authorizer
添加新的业务流程授权者
would need to be modified and clearly
需要进行修改并且清楚
hup hypothetically someone could say why
假设有人可以说为什么
don't we use some generic even like
我们不使用一些通用的
authorization request then we wouldn't
授权请求，那么我们不会
need to modify anything okay but if we
需要修改任何内容，但是如果我们
in general events should mean something
在一般情况下应该意味着
to business does authorization requested
对企业进行授权请求
mean anything to business in our case
在我们的情况下对业务毫无意义
very not maybe you have any cases where
非常可能你没有任何情况
it does anyway authorization requested
无论如何，它会执行授权请求
message let's call it a message it's
消息，我们称它为消息
dedicated to one particular service it
致力于一项特定的服务
is no any other service is not supposed
没有任何其他服务是不应该的
to read this so it's a direct message
阅读这是直接的消息
and what's more is an imperative because
而且当务之急是因为
we want to perform an action so it's not
我们想执行一个动作，所以它不是
an even it's a comment it would be a
即使是评论，也将是
wrong usage of the event message pattern
错误使用事件消息模式
but this was just a hypothetical
但这只是一个假设
discussion it depends on on the real use
讨论取决于实际用途
case anyway yet another problem we might
无论如何，我们可能还会遇到另一个问题
spot here is that customer contact needs
此处是客户联系需求
to be aware that there's some ml process
要知道有一些ml过程
going on up there because it needs to
去那里，因为它需要
listen to a ml check succeeded ml check
听毫升检查成功毫升检查
failed events right so whenever we want
失败的事件对，所以无论何时我们想要
to change the order of steps in our
改变我们的步骤顺序
process we would need to modify both of
流程，我们需要同时修改
these components do we have any
这些组件我们有
alternative data yes we do the
替代数据，是的
orchestration which is nothing more than
编排无非就是
just even common transformation pattern
甚至是普通的转换模式
and this is how it works the client
这就是客户端的工作方式
sends the imperative command address
发送命令命令地址
change process and the other strange
改变过程和另一个奇怪
process is actually a new actor in our
过程实际上是我们的新演员
web sequence diagram and the others
网络序列图及其他
change process is an Orchestrator
变更流程是协调者
business process Orchestrator his role
业务流程协调员的角色
is to make decisions what should be done
是决定应该做什么
next which comments should be sent to
接下来应将评论发送到
which service and the client sends the
哪个服务和客户端发送
imperative command to address change
应对变化的命令性命令
process this in turn is sent through the
依次通过
message bust
消息破灭
authorizer others authorize others
授权他人授权他人
change the authorizer sends the even
更改授权者发送的偶数
back and Orchestrator reads the event
返回，Orchestrator读取事件
and makes the decision what should be
并决定应该做什么
done next and the next step is to
接下来要做的下一步是
register the address change in customer
在客户中注册地址更改
contact and so he sends through the
联系，所以他通过发送
message bus through some specific
通过一些特定的消息总线
channel a register address change
引导寄存器地址更改
command to customer contact that is
命令给客户的联系方式是
responds with with an even again another
用另一个回应
command goes to AM L AM L response
命令转到AM L AM L响应
another command goes to customer contact
另一个命令与客户联系
and the response gets back to the
然后响应返回到
customer and do you know what Bruce
客户，你知道布鲁斯吗
asked me can we join process
问我可以加入过程吗
Orchestrator others change process with
协调器其他人更改流程
customer contact and the answer is yes
客户联系，答案是肯定的
we can according to hexagonal
我们可以根据六角形
architecture the business logic should
构建业务逻辑应
be independent from application and
与应用程序独立并且
infrastructure layers which are actually
实际上是基础架构层
implemented within the address change
在地址变更内实施
process but it is not always that simple
过程，但并不总是那么简单
then we can actually map the pro
然后我们可以实际映射专业人士
circuits trader with a business service
具有商业服务的电路交易员
want one how do we know if it's possible
想要一个我们如何知道是否可能
to join these components into one
将这些组件整合为一个
actually it should be available to us
实际上它应该对我们可用
after event storming session where we
事件风暴会议之后，我们
could identify core domain we'll get
可以确定我们将获得的核心领域
back to it soon yet another question
回到它很快又一个问题
from Bruce what if anything wrong
来自布鲁斯，如果有什么问题怎么办
happens here right here's kind of a
发生在这里，这有点像
transaction right do we need to store
我们需要存储交易权
the state in the others change process
其他人的状态变化过程
Orchestrator and clearly theoretically
编曲者，理论上很清楚
we don't need to produce the state we
我们不需要产生我们的状态
can use routing slip pattern and send
可以使用路由清单模式并发送
the another steps should be taken and
应该采取的其他步骤，
message headers for example by clearly
邮件标题，例如通过清楚
practically and pragmatically we would
实际上，我们会
rather use process manager or saga
而不是使用流程管理器或传奇
pattern and this is what we have here we
模式，这就是我们在这里拥有的
have a saga address change registered
注册一个传奇的地址更改
starts our transaction opens the
开始我们的交易将打开
transaction and based on the result from
交易并基于
AML if the address change is confirmed
如果确认地址更改，则为AML
we commit the transaction or if the AML
我们提交交易或反洗钱
check is negative
检查是否定的
then we recall the other exchange we
然后我们回想起另一场交流
roll back the transaction and regarding
回滚交易，并考虑
the persistence and that the engine of
持久性和引擎
the orchestrator we we might have new
我们可能有新的协调员
resorption we can use relational
我们可以使用关系吸收
databases we can use actor model we can
我们可以使用参与者模型的数据库
use Finnish state machine we can use
使用芬兰的状态机，我们可以使用
some custom solutions and yes we can
一些自定义解决方案，是的，我们可以
also use activity for example how does
也使用活动例如
it look like from architectural
从建筑上看
perspective I was emitted don't worry
观点，我被释放不用担心
the green components are micro services
绿色组件是微服务
that are common to all all our business
这是我们所有业务的共同点
processes to all business processes well
到所有业务流程的流程
the Queen ones are business process
女王是业务流程
related imagine this is green the flow
相关想象一下这是绿色的人流
is pretty similar to what we've seen in
与我们在
with VP MS user interacts with our
VP MS用户与我们互动
system through some finds you eyes and
通过一些系统发现你的眼睛和
ends up in UI control with you a
最终出现在您的UI控件中
controller does is it forwards commands
控制器所做的就是转发命令
through Apache Kafka in tower pro
通过Tower Pro中的Apache Kafka
circuits traders like others change
像其他人一样巡回交易
process and forwards requests to our
处理并将请求转发给我们
common components like history tasks
常见组件，例如历史记录任务
place reports on user or user an access
将报告放在用户或用户访问权限上
manager what is interesting here is that
经理这里有趣的是
these components they create grid models
这些组件创建了网格模型
for you a controller by reading events
通过阅读事件为您提供控制器
from address change process from
从地址更改过程
purchases orchestrators doesn't it sound
购买协调器听起来不对
like secure s it is secure s we are
像安全s一样安全s我们是
sending commands here animate events
在此处发送命令动画事件
process related events which are
处理相关事件
consumed over here in order to produce
在这里消费以生产
read modes this is secure s an
读取模式是安全的
interesting is also the component right
有趣的也是正确的组件
user an access manager which was part of
用户是属于的访问管理器
the same model at before and now is
以前和现在的相同模型是
separate from the process service
与流程服务分开
trainer why is it okay because processor
培训师为什么还可以，因为处理器
castrator does not care about how the
施法者不在乎
authorization part is actually
授权部分实际上是
implemented the only thing he needs to
实现了他唯一需要做的
know is what is the which user is
知道什么是哪个用户
actually trying to perform some action
实际上试图执行一些动作
what happens next is that the others
接下来发生的是其他人
change process the procedure castrator
更改过程程序施法者
sends comment further to business micro
向Business Micro发送更多评论
services like ultra authorize your
诸如超授权服务
customer contact a ml and reads events
客户联系毫升并读取事件
that they
他们
myth and each microservice manage their
神话和每个微服务管理自己的
own data in your own databases with
在您自己的数据库中拥有自己的数据
their own schemas etc and I mentioned
他们自己的模式等，我提到
Kafka and Bruce knows Kafka Allah it
卡夫卡和布鲁斯知道卡夫卡真主
knows before performance that all its
在表演之前就知道
advantages but he wonders why it is good
优势，但他想知道为什么它很好
in our case to use Kafka how can help in
在我们的情况下使用Kafka如何提供帮助
our case well and we can actually find
我们的案子很好，我们实际上可以找到
at least three reasons for that first of
至少有以下三个原因
all consumer groups our processors
所有消费者群体我们的加工商
orchestrators can listen to events not
协调员不能听事件
competing with any other listeners that
与其他听众竞争
might be somewhere here it won't
可能在这里某处
interact interrupt any her ography that
互动中断了她的任何摄影
is happening over here it will be acting
发生在这里它将行动
within its own consumer group that's the
在自己的消费群体中
first thing second thing is scalability
第一件事第二件事是可伸缩性
backed by topic partitioning if you have
如果有的话，以主题划分为后盾
like 10 partitions for a topic we may
例如一个主题的10个分区
have up to 10 instances of our process
最多有10个流程实例
Orchestrator and finally Kafka streams
协调器，最后是卡夫卡流
which is a fantastic tool for building
这是构建的绝佳工具
streams and views and we will get back
流和视图，我们会回来的
to the graphical streams as well um
以及图形流
Bruce has another question how can we
布鲁斯还有另一个问题，我们怎么能
deliver new business process do we
交付新的业务流程
always need to modify this common
总是需要修改这个共同点
components like tasks Lee's history and
像李的历史任务和
reports if we would need to modify them
报告是否需要修改它们
every time we would rather have a
每次我们宁愿有一个
distributed model it rather than micro
分布式模型而不是微观模型
services so the answer is rather use
服务，所以答案是使用
conventional reconfiguration what I mean
常规重新配置我的意思是
by this is that we could establish a set
通过这一点，我们可以建立一套
of generic events that would inform us
可以告诉我们的一般事件
about in which possible state the
关于哪种可能的状态
process currently is to be specific what
当前的过程具体是什么
kind of events could be process instance
一种事件可能是流程实例
created processes instance cancelled
创建的流程实例已取消
tasks created that's assigned that's
创建的任务分配的是
completed so thanks to this we leave
完成，因此，我们离开
ourselves an option to choose the
我们自己可以选择
different Orchestrator to choose
不同的Orchestrator可供选择
different Orchestrator
不同的协调器
engines to experiment with them we may
引擎进行实验，我们可能
use simple if I if else statements if
如果我if else else if
the process is very simple we may use
这个过程非常简单，我们可以使用
akka we may use active
我们可能会使用主动
or any other engine we like just
或我们喜欢的任何其他引擎
following these conventions and the
遵循这些约定和
question from Bruce who will control
来自布鲁斯的问题，谁来控制
this convention the team will because a
这项约定，团队将因为
team is responsible for the process end
团队负责流程的结束
to end and team won't be happy ever
结束，团队永远不会幸福
process is not visible in history or in
该过程在历史记录或历史记录中不可见
or in the task list so we do take care
或在任务列表中，所以我们要小心
of it believe me
其中相信我
good another question from Bruce how
好来自布鲁斯的另一个问题
would you implement the orchestrator and
您会实施协调器吗？
I would suggest using spring closed
我建议使用弹簧关闭
stream there were at least two talks
串流至少有两个讲座
mentioning Spring clouds stream this
提到春天的云流
morning so I won't dig too deep into
早上，这样我就不会深入
into details but in a nutshell sprinkle
进入细节，但概括地说
stream is library providing an
流是提供
abstraction over messaging middlewares
消息中间件的抽象
like Kafka for example enabling
例如Kafka，例如启用
declarative defining of communication
声明式的沟通定义
channels what you can see actually on
引导您实际看到的内容
the slide what our orchestrate
幻灯片是我们精心策划的
Orchestrator does is that it
Orchestrator所做的就是
communicates it listens to commands on
进行通信，侦听命令
others change processes channel topic
其他更改流程频道主题
and it amazed events on generic process
它使通用过程中的事件惊奇
events topic and business services also
活动主题和业务服务也
have one topic one channel for amazing
有一个主题，一个频道令人惊叹
events one channel for listening to
事件一个频道收听
commands
命令
and what's more sprinkle stream has also
还有更多的洒水流
fantastic support for testing such
出色的测试支持
communication automatic testing and it
通讯自动测试及其
is supported by distributed tracing
分布式跟踪支持
library spring called sleuth and
库弹簧叫侦探和
contract testing from spring cloud
Spring Cloud的合约测试
contract as well so sprinkles stream in
也会收缩
is an invaluable tool from spring
是春季的宝贵工具
ecosystem in this kind of solutions
这种解决方案中的生态系统
Bruce is still not satisfied and asks
布鲁斯仍然不满意，问
how would I know that this particular
我怎么知道这个特殊的
event emitted by one particular business
一个特定企业发出的事件
micro service is actually related to my
微服务实际上与我的
business process and not to the other
业务流程而不是其他
yet by another convention
另一个约定
what is this convention well a process
这个惯例是什么过程
Orchestrator sending command can enhance
Orchestrator发送命令可以增强
the message with all information that
带有所有信息的消息
are necessary to uniquely identify the
是唯一识别
process instance and regardless if it
流程实例，无论是否
a message header or if it's a regular
邮件标题或常规标题
part of the payload it doesn't matter it
负载的一部分无关紧要
needs to be added to the message and
需要添加到邮件中
what business microservice does is it is
企业微服务所要做的是
just to take this header and send it
只是拿这个头发送
back with even doesn't look similar to
连看起来都不像
what's printed out
打印什么
it looks in our next question from Bruce
它出现在布鲁斯的下一个问题中
how would I get tasks assigned to user
我如何将任务分配给用户
and here comes Kafka streams
卡夫卡溪流来了
Kafka streams is a lightweight a
卡夫卡流是一个轻量级的
lightweight library built on top of the
建立在
Kafka consumer and Kafka producer and it
卡夫卡消费者和卡夫卡生产者及其
lets us calculate stream publish events
让我们计算流发布事件
and other topics make aggregations
和其他主题进行汇总
windowing filtering and many many other
窗口过滤和许多其他
stuff and regarding task lists what you
东西，关于任务清单，你有什么
can see here is that we could
可以看到这里是我们可以
declaratively define how we consume the
声明性地定义我们如何消费
generic process events topic how we
通用流程事件主题是我们如何
group messages that are being sent there
分组发送到那里的消息
how we filter them and finally how we
我们如何过滤它们，最后我们如何
build the read model and actually this
建立读取模型，实际上
is how we do this is how we make we'd
这就是我们的方法这就是我们的方法
moles in vattenfall every day we read we
每天我们都在阅读vattenfall中的痣
build read moles in that way we utilize
以这种方式建立阅读痣
Kafka streams a lot and it's very
卡夫卡流很多，这是非常
powerful to believe me does this work
坚信我会做这项工作
the same way in terms of reports yes it
就报告而言也是一样
does you can utilize Kafka streams you
你可以利用卡夫卡流吗
can for example use MongoDB or Cassandra
例如可以使用MongoDB或Cassandra
to actually store the view the read
实际存储视图的读取
mobile-optimized views over here you can
您可以在此处针对移动设备进行优化的视图
scala can use part you can use some
Scala可以使用一部分，也可以使用一些
machine learning and you can with this
机器学习，你可以用这个
you get so much technical autonomy then
您将获得如此多的技术自主权
you could produce reports that business
您可以产生有关业务的报告
have never dreamt of that no vendor will
从来没有梦想过没有供应商会
ever provide you with an off-the-shelf
曾经为您提供现成的
DBMS solution how can Bruce monitor its
DBMS解决方案布鲁斯如何监控其
services and according to the article by
服务，并根据文章
martin fowler entitled micro service
马丁·福勒题为《微服务》
prerequisites before we go into micro
我们进入微观的先决条件
services we should actually provide the
我们实际上应该提供的服务
basic monitoring the basic observability
基本监控基本可观察性
so assuming that bruce already has that
所以假设布鲁斯已经有了
yes
是
structure we to say that there are
我们说的结构有
countless possibilities but if we were
无数的可能性，但如果我们是
around the spring toaster the very basic
春季烤面包机周围非常基本
a massive library sprinkles Luthor
庞大的图书馆撒满Luthor
distributed tracing and there was
分布式跟踪，并且
actually a talk yesterday about that and
昨天实际上是在谈论
in a big short the sleuth does works in
在短短的时间内，侦探确实在
a way that whenever we are sending
无论何时我们发送
anything any message there's a trace EDA
任何消息，都有EDA追踪
spine he added so we can very easily
他加了脊椎，所以我们可以很容易地
trace the route of all our requests so
跟踪我们所有请求的路线，以便
that we know which for example compound
我们知道哪个化合物
in our system failed in our business
我们系统中的业务失败
process management in order to use this
流程管理以便使用此
company
公司
sorry to use this library to make it
很抱歉使用这个库来制作它
useful we need to have a central place
有用，我们需要有一个中心位置
where we can actually search for those
我们可以在那里实际搜索
logs and one of the possibilities one of
日志和可能性之一
the examples would be elastic search
例子是弹性搜索
locks of cabaa stock or we can actually
卡巴尼亚股票的锁，否则我们实际上可以
search for the locks and the perform
搜索锁和执行
locks we could monitor latency between
锁，我们可以监视之间的延迟
our services or dependencies with Zipkin
我们与Zipkin的服务或依赖关系
we can use micrometer Prometheus and we
我们可以使用千分尺普罗米修斯，我们
can even take one step further for
甚至可以进一步
semantic monitoring which is about
语义监控是关于
running tests on our living production
对我们的生活产品进行测试
environment and checking if our business
环境并检查我们的业务
our critical business processes work um
我们的关键业务流程
remember we said that people are
记得我们说过
essential part of micro services who
微服务必不可少的部分
should be the owner of the process then
应该是该过程的所有者
and we kind of answered this question a
我们有点回答了这个问题
bit ideally it would be best if the
理想情况下，如果
whole process is managed by one single
整个过程由一个人管理
team if the process Orchestrator can be
团队，如果流程协调员可以
managed one-to-one with some business
与某些业务一对一管理
micro service then the problem that then
微服务那么那个问题
they can even be merged into one
他们甚至可以合并为一个
application and the problem is gone but
应用程序，问题消失了，但是
when the process crosses multi primary
当过程跨多主
services then we should carefully think
服务，那么我们应该仔细考虑
what is the real core part of the
真正的核心部分是什么
process and this is where even storming
过程，这就是猛冲的地方
helps us because then we can identify
帮助我们，因为这样我们可以确定
the core domain and in our case in our
核心领域，就我们而言
example that you can see in the other
你可以在另一个例子中看到的例子
exchange process the customer contact is
客户联系的交换过程是
the core domain the AML or authorizer
AML或授权者的核心域
we're just supporting a generic
我们只是支持通用
subdomain but this is
子域，但这是
yep clearly hypothetical discussion
是的，显然是假想的讨论
because it will depend on your use cases
因为这取决于您的用例
or your real business but I have one
或您的真实业务，但我有一个
message to you always try to make only
给您的讯息总是尽量只
one team responsible for the business
一个负责业务的团队
process because this is the only way to
过程，因为这是唯一的方法
provide true team's autonomy do you know
提供真正的团队自治权吗
what Bruce asked me where did you get
布鲁斯问我你在哪里得到的
that solution from enterprise
企业提供的解决方案
integration patterns even message
集成模式甚至消息
process management process manager
流程管理流程经理
transactional client and many other
交易客户和许多其他
patterns that I don't even remember
我什至不记得的模式
their names but everything has already
他们的名字，但一切已经
been identified and described years ago
在几年前被确定和描述
we just took these patterns and apply
我们只是采用了这些模式并应用
them to our problem let's sum things up
他们对我们的问题，让我们总结一下
we might still have common UI that the
我们可能仍然有通用的用户界面
business is really looking for but this
企业真的在寻找，但这
time it no longer needs to be clicked by
时间不再需要单击
our back-end developers it could be
我们的后端开发人员
developed by fronting guys and it can
由前沿人士开发，它可以
become not only for our business process
不仅成为我们的业务流程
but but for all systems we have in
但对于我们拥有的所有系统
company as it is ours if not it does not
公司是我们的，如果不是的话
belong to any vendor reports with our
属于我们的任何供应商报告
technological autonomy we can get we can
我们可以得到的技术自主权
provide reports that any vendor will
提供任何供应商将提供的报告
give us we can have any process modeler
给我们，我们可以有任何流程建模者
we like that support UML or VP amen but
我们喜欢支持UML或VP阿门，但是
it doesn't matter
没关系
the only mole that will give us value
唯一能给我们带来价值的痣
will be the one that landed on the wall
将是落在墙上的那个
with the sticky note you know why
用便签，你知道为什么
because then we actually communicate
因为那时我们实际上在交流
with each other we speak with these
彼此，我们用这些说话
business people we fight for the
我们为之奋斗的商务人士
knowledge we don't rely on just some
我们不仅仅依赖某些知识
simple diagrams from analysts from some
来自一些分析师的简单图表
proxy analysts or proxy product owners
代理分析师或代理产品所有者
we are part of this knowledge and this
我们是这种知识的一部分
is the real model system integration we
是我们真正的模型系统集成
don't need to have any connectors there
不需要那里有任何连接器
you can use stress template web client
您可以使用压力模板网络客户端
from ref locks sprinkle stream whatever
来自ref lock的流洒什么
it like and instead of having one black
它喜欢而不是只有一个黑色
box in the form of workflow engine we
框形式的工作流引擎我们
didn't have numerous pro circuits
没有很多专业电路
traitor's numerous black boxes
叛徒无数黑匣子
one box per one business process does
每个业务流程一个盒子
this solution apply to micro service
此解决方案适用于微服务
autonomy thanks to the fact that instead
自治归功于事实
of having one central workflow engine we
拥有一个中央工作流引擎
have numerous independent pros circus
有众多独立的专业人士
traders we may independently deploy our
交易员，我们可以独立部署我们的
processes not impacting all the others
流程不影响其他所有流程
such approach also lets us separate data
这种方法也使我们可以分离数据
because each business process will
因为每个业务流程都会
manage data itself can have different
管理数据本身可以有不同
schema independent schemas and having
独立于模式的模式，并具有
such independent services executing
这样的独立服务执行
business processes the failure of one
业务流程之一的失败
business process does not necessarily
业务流程不一定
need to cause the global system failure
需要引起全局系统故障
so we have the resilience of tunnel
所以我们有隧道的弹性
what about scalability we can scale our
关于可扩展性，我们可以扩展我们的规模
services independently the pro circuits
独立服务专业电路
trailer is a micro service we can scale
拖车是我们可以扩展的微服务
it independently from any other services
它独立于任何其他服务
so we have scalability autonomy separate
所以我们有独立的可扩展性自主权
process orchestrators lets us also
过程协调器还使我们
choose technology of a choice let us use
选择一种选择的技术让我们使用
technologies that are appropriate for
适用于的技术
the complexity of the business problems
业务问题的复杂性
that we are currently solving so we made
我们目前正在解决，所以我们做了
also experiment with these technologies
也尝试这些技术
we may use different tools for different
我们可能会针对不同的情况使用不同的工具
pro circuits traders that's why we can
专业电路交易员，这就是为什么我们可以
be more competitive in the market and
在市场上更具竞争力
finally people people taking care of the
最后人们照顾的人
process and and working on separate code
处理和处理单独的代码
bases will no longer be afraid of
基地将不再害怕
producing any change of breaking the
产生任何破坏
whole system and even if the one process
整个系统，即使一个过程
depends on the other as in the relation
取决于对方
of sub process for example we can for
例如，我们可以
example apply contract testing so we
例如，应用合同测试，因此我们
know that something is wrong before we
在我们知道某事之前
go live and even if you're alive and
活下去，即使你还活着
something bad happens
坏事发生了
there are numerous patterns to stop the
有很多模式可以阻止
cascading failures small processes small
级联故障小过程小
services means low level of entry for
服务意味着低水平的进入
newcomers low cost of change
新移民的低成本成本
organizational scalability and these are
组织的可扩展性，这些是
only few advantages of what we can
我们所能拥有的仅有的几项优势
achieve with this solution
用这个解决方案实现
and Bruce is now very happy he knows the
布鲁斯现在很高兴，他知道
importance of business proxies within
内部业务代理的重要性
his company he knows the real pain
他的公司，他知道真正的痛苦
points you know where the company gains
你知道公司的收获点
value when it loses value when the
当它失去价值时
company earns money when it loses money
公司亏本赚钱
what are the business rules that drives
驱动什么业务规则
the business that makes the company
创造公司的业务
competitive and he applies real micro
有竞争力，他运用了真正的微观
services autonomous from the
自主的服务
perspectives of scalability data
可伸缩性数据的观点
technology resilience deployment and
技术弹性部署和
people and he uses latest technologies
人，他使用最新技术
appropriate to the class of problem to
适合于问题类别
complexity of problem that is his
他的问题的复杂性
currently solving and changes are done
当前解决和更改已完成
hype at highest possible pace you know
以最快的速度进行宣传
what Bruce colleagues that actually left
布鲁斯同事实际上留下了什么
the company I won't need to come back to
我不需要回去的公司
work on this new micro service engine
在这个新的微服务引擎上工作
and before I say thank you I really
在我说谢谢之前，我真的
encourage you to have a look at new DDD
鼓励您看看新的DDD
by examples project called library' that
通过名为图书馆的示例项目
we created together with Jakob P Lehmann
我们与Jakob P Lehmann共同创造
from pivotal and it is a comprehensive
从关键到全面
example showing or a step-by-step
示例展示或分步介绍
journey to deliver a software solution
提供软件解决方案的旅程
using big picture events storming using
使用大图事件猛烈使用
example mapping design level tactical
示例映射设计级别战术
even storming including the process of
甚至暴风雨，包括
choosing the right aggregates for
选择合适的骨料
example and many many more so please
例子还有很多，所以请
find us on github and once again thank
在github上找到我们，再次感谢
you very much and I hope to see you next
非常感谢你，我希望下次见
year thank
年感谢
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]